<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-02T21:29:46-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jelani The…</title><subtitle>Sharing insights from my travels, work, and life experiences. Hopefully I can help others in their lives with what I share and in sharing I can learn more about my blind spots.</subtitle><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Readme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/02/README/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Readme" /><published>2023-03-02T20:16:52-03:00</published><updated>2023-03-02T20:16:52-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/02/README</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/02/README/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;_drafts&quot;&gt;_drafts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This directory &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_drafts&lt;/code&gt; is used to store all draft posts. Once the draft is finished prefix the file with a date in the following format, yyyy-mm-dd, and move to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">_drafts</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Do Not Disturb</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2023/03/02/do-not-disturb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do Not Disturb" /><published>2023-03-02T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2023/03/02/do-not-disturb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2023/03/02/do-not-disturb/">&lt;p&gt;Current setting, I’m sitting on my balcony in Sao Paulo, Brazil listening to Don Toliver’s Love Struck Deluxe. I just finished eating a bun-less burger bowl with some quinoa and whatever else it had, while drinking some red wine (maybe I’ll remember to pre-read this before I upload it and fill in what kind of red wine it is, just know that it’s dry). It’s a peaceful night with a beautiful skyline and an interesting haze in the distance, perfect environment for me to get in one of these moods when I start to reflect and think about life, what I want out of it, and how close/far I am to achieving the things I want out if it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This usually isn’t much of an event anymore, probably why I haven’t written in a while, but today is a little bit different. Like the grandmasters of chess, a game in which I’m not as proficient, in the real world version of such I’m continuously calculating what I need to do to achieve what I want. The quark with that is that I want so many things. That’s not fair to say, it’s not things that I’m after, but more so an equilibrium. A state where I can have the best of many worlds. Impossible, I’m not so sure about that “the difficult we do immediately, the impossible takes a little longer.” The biggest part of my wants is where do I want to be geographically and tied to that is what kind of work I want to do (I may or may not be interviewing for other… “experiences” at this time). I want to be in a place where I have community, I don’t think this part has ever changed for me really. I want this place to have all of the vibes, but also be safe. Of course as a “digital nomad” one of the hallmarks that rates places higher on the totem poll is cost of living. This isn’t always the case, but sometimes cost of living and safety may butt heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the location out of the way the second part of that was the type of work. I am and have been fortunate enough to choose a field/career that affords me opportunities to do things that I would’ve never dreamed of and for that I’m grateful, &lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt; the downside to that, yes there’s a downside, is that finding other opportunities where you have all of the benefits that you currently have along with the compensation expectations becomes increasingly more difficult. You become accustomed to &lt;em&gt;all of the things.&lt;/em&gt; So I can choose to work at a place where I get to go and finally visit Asia and work during local hours, but without the dinero I’m accustomed to or I can say I’ll catch Asia another time and my current stance is the latter. Random aside, I just ordered another bottle of wine and it’s Malbec. I’m probably not going to go back up and insert that above so if you’ve made it this far congrats. So yeah, Asia I’ll see you when I see you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of my “wants” is while I want to be able to be in a place with all of the vibes, that’s safe, where I have a community, I still want it to be affordable enough for me to still be able to say “hey, I’m going to peace out for about 2 or 3 months.” When I think of that “place” where I get those things a few places come to mind. By default I’ll add Fort Lauderdale, Florida solely because I kind of miss living at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=society+las+olas&amp;amp;client=firefox-b-d&amp;amp;sxsrf=AJOqlzUd97I1wuySPo50PBHweKcmN70sZg:1677800915563&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwj1uc28t779AhW6rpUCHSiOBR0Q_AUoAnoECAIQBA&amp;amp;biw=1440&amp;amp;bih=790&amp;amp;dpr=2&quot;&gt;Society Las Olas&lt;/a&gt;. Excluding the random dog shit in the elevators, the car break-ins, people getting stuck in elevators, people busting their ass on that slippery ass tile surrounding the pool, etc… it was kind of a vibe, shout out to the Black Secret Society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up would probably be Medellin, Colombia just because I’ve spent quite a bit of time there, especially because of COVID (Jan 2020 - Dec 2020) so maybe I have a bit of Stockholm syndrome. A place in Europe could be that place for me, but only for 3 months due to Schengen restraints and that’s where I got to when I decided that, even though I like to plan things out, where I am currently in terms of my &lt;del&gt;job&lt;/del&gt; experience search and having quite a few shorter trips already planned that there’s no way I can even predict that I’ll have the ability to even do that in the future. What if I “sell-out” and decide to get an “experience” where the compensation is there, but I have to sacrifice the travels, is it possible, sure, is it likely, na player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I believe it’s possible to achieve what I’m after, I’d be lying if I said that I don’t think about what if I’m wasting time. Opportunity cost is a real thing, I could get to the end of my search and at the end of all that say it wasn’t worth it, but at least I would know. Maybe that’s enough for me, to know that I searched and worked for something even if it turned out to not be what I expect. Maybe that’s the way of the alchemist.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">Current setting, I’m sitting on my balcony in Sao Paulo, Brazil listening to Don Toliver’s Love Struck Deluxe. I just finished eating a bun-less burger bowl with some quinoa and whatever else it had, while drinking some red wine (maybe I’ll remember to pre-read this before I upload it and fill in what kind of red wine it is, just know that it’s dry). It’s a peaceful night with a beautiful skyline and an interesting haze in the distance, perfect environment for me to get in one of these moods when I start to reflect and think about life, what I want out of it, and how close/far I am to achieving the things I want out if it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Blossom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2022/12/18/to-blossom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Blossom" /><published>2022-12-18T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2022/12/18/to-blossom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2022/12/18/to-blossom/">_This was written on a prior date just scheduled to be released on this date so I could be far removed from whatever I was feeling at the time of writing this_

There&apos;s always been this weird feeling I get whenever I&apos;ve spent time at home for a period of time, that time frame being at least a week, sometimes it feels like less. The last time I&apos;ve put that thought out into the either I used the word suffocating. If I had to think of the words or phrases to explain what I mean by that I would say that it feels like I&apos;ve outgrown the environment and that feeling of suffocation is more of a claustrophobia because there isn&apos;t anymore room for growth here for me. It&apos;s not like it&apos;s a one time feeling that I have or once in a blue moon, but every time I&apos;m back it&apos;s the same feeling. Being very in tune with myself and how I feel about things this is the only sign I&apos;ve ever really needed in guiding me on what&apos;s next.

Looking back on some of my other writings last year (2021) I can see that it was me giving my best effort to do what&apos;s &quot;expected&quot; to some degree. Like when people ask when are you going to settle down, the first question that arises after that is when are you going to pick a place to settle in as if settling down necessarily means being stationary. I tried it, it was cool, but I don&apos;t think it&apos;s for me, at least not in the United States at this time. The reason behind that is a little more nuanced. If we think about this collection of narratives, I believe it was in [YOLO Maybe](/life/2021/12/31/yolo-maybe/) where I said that at the end of 2019 I felt like I was hitting my stride and then 2020 happened. This present moment feels like the end of 2019 except three years into the future. Just like then I&apos;ll be bringing in the new year in a different country (Argentina as opposed to Peru) with a very rough itinerary ahead.

My &quot;journey&quot; has quite a few parallels between two books that I need to reacquaint myself with, one being [The Alchemist](https://a.co/d/blEJf9e) and the other being [Outwitting the Devil](https://a.co/d/2eYayXG). Like Santiago from The Alchemist I&apos;m following my personal legend in search of my &quot;pyramids&quot;, but unlike Santiago my &quot;pyramids&quot; isn&apos;t at the start of my journey. The parallels in regards to Outwitting the Devil aren&apos;t as easy to point out like The Alchemist, rather there are themes that I&apos;m aware. The biggest is the difference between drifters and non-drifters which has stuck with me from the first time I read it amd the other another part that stuck out to me being how non-drifters are constantly under attack by the &quot;Devil&quot;, along with his drifters, to convert them into drifters. Was this a tangent? Yo no se, pero what I can tell you is that I&apos;m ready to go the distance with this journey. Where it will end and how? No idea, but I&apos;m sure however it does it&apos;ll either be a masterpiece or a great ball of fire and I&apos;m fine with it either way.</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">This was written on a prior date just scheduled to be released on this date so I could be far removed from whatever I was feeling at the time of writing this</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">36 for 36</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2022/12/01/36-for-36/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="36 for 36" /><published>2022-12-01T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2022/12/01/36-for-36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2022/12/01/36-for-36/">How good and how pleasant it is to grow old with a young soul. People focused on aging themselves too quickly that&apos;s why I&apos;m gung ho about traveling and experiencing life while I still have time. This isn&apos;t an open letter about something devastating where my life flashed before my eyes. Just a recurring realization that nothing is promised. We&apos;re here for a blink of an eye, the moment is here, and then it&apos;s gone. [Two years ago today](/life/2020/12/01/34/) my time living in Colombia due to COVID was coming to an end. I just remembered how uncertain everything was at the time of writing. Little did I know that I would immediately come back to the States and have a bout with COVID. Nor did I know that I would decide to spend 13 months living in Ft Lauderdale and later decide let me get back to traveling pretty much most of 2022. I had no idea that any of the things that occurred would occur, but what I did know was that I would/could never get time back and that I can&apos;t/shouldn&apos;t wait for others to aid in my happiness or the fulfilling life I want to live. I mean, it&apos;s **my happiness**, what sense would it make to give someone else the power over something so important to me. What&apos;s in store for the next two years? Well I have a pretty loose plan. In the end of 2022 and most of 2023 I will travel to Argentina, Brazil, Colombia, Mexico, Portugal, Spain, Netherlands, as well as a the continent of Africa (haven&apos;t figured out the countries yet). I&apos;ll continue to be a non-drifter as mentioned in my other posts and continuing to enjoy life.

It&apos;s funny how today has been super cool and I have this seemingly intrinsic motivation to write something because... well I haven&apos;t written in a while. Then I start and I&apos;m like... eh... yeah I don&apos;t know if I care that much to continue. I guess it&apos;s an evolution type of deal where I begin to question, what is this for? Who is this for? Maybe when I figure that out I&apos;ll write a post about it or not. Anyway, time to hit up club bed so I can get in the gym in the morning. Trying to focus on aging gracefully and I&apos;ve found a new love, if you will, for the gym. I&apos;ve been more consistent than I&apos;ve ever been, probably because how much shit I was talking about people doing wordle daily, but not being able to create a new habit. Most of the time if you see me post something like that chances are I&apos;m talking ot myself. Anyway, stay you, live life, and do weird things.

Random shout out to Rafa for the shirt when his dog put her pretty little paws on my white shirt. That was a cool day in Guatape jumping off of bridges (yup, totally did it) and kicking it with cool people #RemoteYear

![rafa_shirt][rafa_shirt]

[rafa_shirt]: {{site.images_url}}/36-for-36/rafa_shirt.jpg</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">How good and how pleasant it is to grow old with a young soul. People focused on aging themselves too quickly that’s why I’m gung ho about traveling and experiencing life while I still have time. This isn’t an open letter about something devastating where my life flashed before my eyes. Just a recurring realization that nothing is promised. We’re here for a blink of an eye, the moment is here, and then it’s gone. Two years ago today my time living in Colombia due to COVID was coming to an end. I just remembered how uncertain everything was at the time of writing. Little did I know that I would immediately come back to the States and have a bout with COVID. Nor did I know that I would decide to spend 13 months living in Ft Lauderdale and later decide let me get back to traveling pretty much most of 2022. I had no idea that any of the things that occurred would occur, but what I did know was that I would/could never get time back and that I can’t/shouldn’t wait for others to aid in my happiness or the fulfilling life I want to live. I mean, it’s my happiness, what sense would it make to give someone else the power over something so important to me. What’s in store for the next two years? Well I have a pretty loose plan. In the end of 2022 and most of 2023 I will travel to Argentina, Brazil, Colombia, Mexico, Portugal, Spain, Netherlands, as well as a the continent of Africa (haven’t figured out the countries yet). I’ll continue to be a non-drifter as mentioned in my other posts and continuing to enjoy life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meditations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2022/06/12/meditations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meditations" /><published>2022-06-12T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2022/06/12/meditations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2022/06/12/meditations/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been over 14,083,200 seconds since my last post. What’s changed since “YOLO Maybe?” Quite a bit and also not much. What’s the same? Well, I’m still playing chess on a board without any opposing pieces, except I see opposing pieces there. They are representations of many things ranging from ways that I hinder or sabotage myself, opinions from others whom I care about in regards to potential judgment, and fears of who I’ll hurt by making myself happy. I still have the hunger/passion for travel even though I am aware of what that might do to all forms of relationships, at least at this time. (intermission it’s 12 AM here and gotta do this Wordle)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.jelanithe.com/media/images/2022-06-12-meditations/wordle.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Wordle&quot; title=&quot;Wordle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where was I? Oh yeah, the things that are the same. Still giving my best in all of the things from getting better at my craft as an engineer, working on my dancing (salsa, bachata, etc…), y practicando mi espanol. I think that’s where &lt;em&gt;the same&lt;/em&gt; ends. So what’s new? Well, I’m no longer living in Ft Lauderdale even though I do miss it for a multitude of reasons. I’m back on the road or air depending on the slang you want to use. Writing this in Tulum as I try to process some things. I’ve found an appreciation for the C word (Consistency) for which without nothing is really possible. New property management, new (hopefully) non shitty tenants. Losing old non-productive habits, while forming new productive ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I live life, the more lessons I learn, and the more lessons I learn the more those opposing chess pieces continue to fade. I find myself in that place like the single lily pad in a pond starting its takeover of that pond. The eventual explosion of growth cannot yet be seen, but it is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">It’s been over 14,083,200 seconds since my last post. What’s changed since “YOLO Maybe?” Quite a bit and also not much. What’s the same? Well, I’m still playing chess on a board without any opposing pieces, except I see opposing pieces there. They are representations of many things ranging from ways that I hinder or sabotage myself, opinions from others whom I care about in regards to potential judgment, and fears of who I’ll hurt by making myself happy. I still have the hunger/passion for travel even though I am aware of what that might do to all forms of relationships, at least at this time. (intermission it’s 12 AM here and gotta do this Wordle)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YOLO Maybe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/12/31/yolo-maybe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YOLO Maybe" /><published>2021-12-31T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2021/12/31/yolo-maybe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/12/31/yolo-maybe/">&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a year!?! 2021 is coming to an end and as most would do I am reflecting on the soon to be previous year as we approach the next. When I cam back from Colombia after spending most of 2020 there here is where I was mentally. My 2019 was the year I broke out of my proverbial shell and started exploring to figure out what kind of life I wanted to forge for myself. I had begun to experience a life long dream I didn’t know I had fully realized nor did I know I would ever when I took that transformative trip to Barcelona back in 2013. Here I am at the end of 2020 having to put my continued exploration of that dream on hold because of the pandemic. Forced with the decision of continuing to travel through the great unknown of COVID or ground myself for a year. I chose the latter. What came with that was a number of new experiences many of which were new and awesome. While grounded, 2021 wasn’t as bad as I thought it would be. It turned into the “gap” year I never had and never knew I needed. It was the year of a new self discovery. It was a year of losing and regaining identities. Breaking the habit of being yourself &amp;lt;- Great book by Joe Dispenza. While this year has been amazing in so many ways it also been taxing. At the end of 2019 I felt like I was finally hitting my stride in becoming more of myself then the first season of 2020 happened and I had to leave my true adventures in the waiting room. Then season 2: 2021 became more of the same, in regards to limiting the scope of adventures, but that hunger and desire for that grander adventure and self discovery has grown to be more than a flicker. What I’m most looking forward to in the new year is to light the night sky with my passion to continue to build upon that growth I saw and felt I was ever approaching at the end of 2019 because this new year won’t be just another 2020 too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Wow, what a year!?! 2021 is coming to an end and as most would do I am reflecting on the soon to be previous year as we approach the next. When I cam back from Colombia after spending most of 2020 there here is where I was mentally. My 2019 was the year I broke out of my proverbial shell and started exploring to figure out what kind of life I wanted to forge for myself. I had begun to experience a life long dream I didn’t know I had fully realized nor did I know I would ever when I took that transformative trip to Barcelona back in 2013. Here I am at the end of 2020 having to put my continued exploration of that dream on hold because of the pandemic. Forced with the decision of continuing to travel through the great unknown of COVID or ground myself for a year. I chose the latter. What came with that was a number of new experiences many of which were new and awesome. While grounded, 2021 wasn’t as bad as I thought it would be. It turned into the “gap” year I never had and never knew I needed. It was the year of a new self discovery. It was a year of losing and regaining identities. Breaking the habit of being yourself &amp;lt;- Great book by Joe Dispenza. While this year has been amazing in so many ways it also been taxing. At the end of 2019 I felt like I was finally hitting my stride in becoming more of myself then the first season of 2020 happened and I had to leave my true adventures in the waiting room. Then season 2: 2021 became more of the same, in regards to limiting the scope of adventures, but that hunger and desire for that grander adventure and self discovery has grown to be more than a flicker. What I’m most looking forward to in the new year is to light the night sky with my passion to continue to build upon that growth I saw and felt I was ever approaching at the end of 2019 because this new year won’t be just another 2020 too.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Random Tuesday at RiverTail</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/10/05/random-tuesday-at-rivertail/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Random Tuesday at RiverTail" /><published>2021-10-05T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2021/10/05/random-tuesday-at-rivertail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/10/05/random-tuesday-at-rivertail/">&lt;p&gt;Is this an impasse? Am I just burnt out? This casamigos anejo double and these dozen oysters are much needed. So what’s new? I’ve been at my current job for just over a year now. My review went as I expected it to go because I know the type of work I put in (humble brag). I’ve been given a golden parachute that I can choose whatever career path I want. Do I want to be a manager? Absolutely not. Do I want to accept the title and responsibilities of a principal engineer where, at this company that means, I oversee all things related technology wise for a product. I’ll put a pin in that. Or continue the journey in my senior role where I have the freedom to knockout work and continue my travel life uninterrupted? I like the way that sounds. Plus not being salary capped by title is also nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So things are mostly good on the job front except for feeling burnt out. Here comes the tangent that I’ll run with. Work is cool, it really is, but I’ve been working on a side project. Hopefully I make the right decisions in regards to this project so that I don’t really have to work in the traditional sense. I guess like most people I’m kind of over it. Not over working in general because I do find an added sense of purpose, but I’d rather be working on things I want to see come to life. Live the life of the learner. Travel to foreign lands, interacting with the people talking about philosophy and whatever worthwhile topics that may arise. Spending time learning and speaking multiple languages to laugh about how we are more alike than different. Cheers to the many worlds we’re all attempting to create for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually the end of my writing, but there’s a dude here at the bar that’s super obnoxious and for some reason he keeps trying to get my attention, as if me writing in my notepad isn’t a sign to stfu and let me continue, to talk about dumb shit. I say dumb based on the other conversations he’s having with the other patrons. By this time I’ve already murked my dozen oysters and am now on my second double of casamigos anejo. Another tangent, who supplies this place with their alcohol because I literally can’t find anejo anywhere. Ok, I’m done for real now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aw baby, stop debating, I’m just a creative
My numbers out of this world
No wonder they got me feeling so alienated”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Is this an impasse? Am I just burnt out? This casamigos anejo double and these dozen oysters are much needed. So what’s new? I’ve been at my current job for just over a year now. My review went as I expected it to go because I know the type of work I put in (humble brag). I’ve been given a golden parachute that I can choose whatever career path I want. Do I want to be a manager? Absolutely not. Do I want to accept the title and responsibilities of a principal engineer where, at this company that means, I oversee all things related technology wise for a product. I’ll put a pin in that. Or continue the journey in my senior role where I have the freedom to knockout work and continue my travel life uninterrupted? I like the way that sounds. Plus not being salary capped by title is also nice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/08/29/its-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s Life" /><published>2021-08-29T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-08-29T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2021/08/29/its-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/08/29/its-life/">&lt;p&gt;All these dreams I have, that I’m super afraid to obtain. Once the money and success comes I know I’m not going be the same. Just from the start of writing this I’m already feeling different. Get you a library card for real, I’ll tell anyone who will listen. Listen, you never know in life what you’ll end up missing. I’ve lived some many lifetimes in 9 months is this Christmas?!? So many learnable moments, learned how to express myself and smell the roses. Life’s too short, word to C-Mac and SQL Andy for the notice. So the past 9 months, not symbolic of anything that’s just coincidence, that almost trap situation was many moons ago. What have I learned in that span of time? That I’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/warren-buffett-afghanistan-ovarian-lottery-luck-inequality-higher-taxes-rich-2021-8&quot;&gt;lucky&lt;/a&gt; enough and shouldn’t complain too much. Fortunate enough that I seek &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/individuals/international-taxpayers/foreign-earned-income-exclusion#:~:text=Foreign%2Dearned%20income%3A%20Foreign%2D,personal%20services%20rendered%20by%20you.&amp;amp;text=The%20excluded%20amount%20will%20reduce,reduce%20your%20self%2Demployment%20tax.&quot;&gt;knowledge&lt;/a&gt; and try to find ways that I can play this game better. My sole purpose for being observant is to make her wetter. Haha, damn that was uncomfortable. I think about the future and what I want from it. Everyone seeks what they want, but most don’t know what they can give. The knowledge I’ve acquired got me turning 20 grand into 40. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/mc2transport/&quot;&gt;MC2&lt;/a&gt; is a conduit, but there’s more for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.tdameritrade.com/&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;. For those that scoff about me not being a millionaire yet, you gotta start somewhere, going from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Zero-One-Notes-Startups-Future/dp/0804139296&quot;&gt;zero to one&lt;/a&gt;. Said so many words, but said nothing at all. I’m just waiting on spring time to come fall. I love ya’ll, real shit man I love ya’ll. Even the folks I can’t stand to be around. I appreciate your existence because if it wasn’t for you, I wouldn’t do what I could to not be around you. If a tree falls in the forest and no one is around it makes a sound too. Haven’t said much in a minute I wish I could condense things and share more. Almost like a condensed version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wherefor.com/&quot;&gt;where for&lt;/a&gt;. I’m about to do something real different. In this world of the digital age where we’re less connected than ever. () &amp;lt;- here is where I thought about sharing my number. Let’s talk about all things philosophy and figure how to be more lucky. Change the world forever from seeds planted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">All these dreams I have, that I’m super afraid to obtain. Once the money and success comes I know I’m not going be the same. Just from the start of writing this I’m already feeling different. Get you a library card for real, I’ll tell anyone who will listen. Listen, you never know in life what you’ll end up missing. I’ve lived some many lifetimes in 9 months is this Christmas?!? So many learnable moments, learned how to express myself and smell the roses. Life’s too short, word to C-Mac and SQL Andy for the notice. So the past 9 months, not symbolic of anything that’s just coincidence, that almost trap situation was many moons ago. What have I learned in that span of time? That I’m lucky enough and shouldn’t complain too much. Fortunate enough that I seek knowledge and try to find ways that I can play this game better. My sole purpose for being observant is to make her wetter. Haha, damn that was uncomfortable. I think about the future and what I want from it. Everyone seeks what they want, but most don’t know what they can give. The knowledge I’ve acquired got me turning 20 grand into 40. MC2 is a conduit, but there’s more for me. For those that scoff about me not being a millionaire yet, you gotta start somewhere, going from zero to one. Said so many words, but said nothing at all. I’m just waiting on spring time to come fall. I love ya’ll, real shit man I love ya’ll. Even the folks I can’t stand to be around. I appreciate your existence because if it wasn’t for you, I wouldn’t do what I could to not be around you. If a tree falls in the forest and no one is around it makes a sound too. Haven’t said much in a minute I wish I could condense things and share more. Almost like a condensed version of where for. I’m about to do something real different. In this world of the digital age where we’re less connected than ever. () &amp;lt;- here is where I thought about sharing my number. Let’s talk about all things philosophy and figure how to be more lucky. Change the world forever from seeds planted.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Plant the Tree</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/investing/2021/05/19/plant-the-tree/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plant the Tree" /><published>2021-05-19T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-05-19T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/investing/2021/05/19/plant-the-tree</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/investing/2021/05/19/plant-the-tree/">&lt;p&gt;If the best time to plant a tree was 25 years ago, then when would be the next best time to plant a tree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/WRQBXSCnEFJIuxktnw/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Thinking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to that question is now. This question sets the stage for what people seem to &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to do and that’s invest. So let’s start with the definition that speaks to this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.jelanithe.com/media/images/plant-the-tree/invest-definition.png&quot; alt=&quot;Invest definition&quot; title=&quot;Invest definition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the craze of the day being cryptocurrency let me just say that this post won’t be talking about what should be invested in or how you should choose your investment strategy, this will purely talk about investing in a general sense which could be applied to personal endeavors or in a variety of markets because the formula is the same, just the variables are different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merging the first two examples of the definition above we come up with “expend money, one’s time, energy, or effort to a particular undertaking with the expectation of a worthwhile result”, congratulations we’re all investors. Great, we’re all investors so this post is finished right, not quite. All of us are short-term investors and fewer of us are also long-term investors. Example of a short-term investment: I’m sore and I’d like to feel better by paying for a massage, if you don’t have a bae. Example of a long-term investment: I want to learn Spanish because I plan on making Puerto Rico my primary residence due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.districtofcolumbiataxattorney.com/articles/tax-weary-americans-find-haven-in-puerto-rico/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20a%20U.S.%20citizen%20who,on%20dividends%20from%20export%20services.&quot;&gt;4% business/income tax&lt;/a&gt; living in the U.S. territory instead of the tax percentage living in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I continue let me say that there’s nothing wrong with short-term investments, whether it be making a purchase of something you want, buying penny marijuana stocks in hopes to it big, or investing your time watching a mini-series. Short-term anything helps us break the monotony of the long game. The issue comes when people don’t think about the long game at all. Some apprehension in regards to this tends to be about the amount of time it’ll take to reap the benefit of said investment. Let’s stick with the example of learning a new language. Say it takes 2 years to become fluent in a new language (I’m just pulling out 2 years out of thin air). One might say, “2 years is a long time”, but wouldn’t the time pass regardless of if you learned that language, skill, investment strategy, etc? &lt;em&gt;IF&lt;/em&gt; it’s something that you really want to reap then the length of time shouldn’t really matter. Whatever that thing is that you really do care about, start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the random resources in regards to investing financially, books, and other things I liked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/investing-in-index-funds-4771002&quot;&gt;Investing in index funds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/dollarcostaveraging.asp&quot;&gt;Dollar Cost Averaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tastytrade.com/learn&quot;&gt;TastyTrade learning stock options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://optionalpha.com/&quot;&gt;Option alpha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.richdad.com/products/cashflow-classic&quot;&gt;Cashflow Game by Rich Dad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.babypips.com/&quot;&gt;BabyPips: Learning Forex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Slight-Edge-Turning-Disciplines-Happiness/dp/1626340463&quot;&gt;The Slight Edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dip-Little-Book-Teaches-Stick-ebook/dp/B000QCSA54/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=the+dip&amp;amp;qid=1621401784&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;The Dip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="investing" /><summary type="html">If the best time to plant a tree was 25 years ago, then when would be the next best time to plant a tree?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hunger.on.wharfside</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/05/16/hunger-on-wharfside/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hunger.on.wharfside" /><published>2021-05-16T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-05-16T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2021/05/16/hunger-on-wharfside</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2021/05/16/hunger-on-wharfside/">&lt;p&gt;Off in the corner contemplating my way in as it drizzles. Beautiful life ahead of me, but in this moment it doesn’t feel as such. Everyday as I work towards moving myself from where I am to where I’ll ultimately end up takes quite a bit of time, effort, and energy, some of which I feel as though I have been misusing. Part of it is me thinking of futures that wouldn’t exist, the other part is the environment. One influences the other and I’ve been contemplating making a change to the latter which could potentially render the former non-existent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;“The reasonable man adapts himself to the world: the unreasonable one persists in trying to adapt the world to himself. Therefore all progress depends on the unreasonable man.” - George Bernard Shaw&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty can be a great motivator to make things happen, I know this personally really well. Before anything changes one must first conjure (hocus pocus vibes) what about their current state should be changed and what’s the alternative that should take its place. This is the beautiful thing about choice. If you feel your current state of being has reached its expiration or you just don’t like it then you can choose to change it. Sure, some changes can be more immediate than others, but even for less immediate changes there are still actions that can be taken to get you moving in the direction that you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stream done, no longer forcing anything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/fX8WfVeRNfCKEHXBfH/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;What it do baby&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok… here are just a few things I want to say that I’m grateful for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Congrats again big sis (Kisha) on getting your MBA and being able to get some of your time back&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thank you Ken for hitting me up about playing golf, it was a cool time and ended up meeting “No IG” Chase who jumped in with us&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m grateful for the start of Weekly Check Wednesday sponsored by MC2 Transport and my original investment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thank you to the folks that can deal with my type of “weird”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m grateful for the life I’ve been able to curate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m super thankful for being able to be an observer of my own thoughts/feelings to be able to better process them (super underrated)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m grateful for being self-aware (also super underrated)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m thankful that I’ll be able to get back to these travels, maybe sooner than later depending on a few things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.jelanithe.com/media/images/ry-tutu.png&quot; alt=&quot;RYMap&quot; title=&quot;RY Tutu Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I think lastly what I’m grateful for is that with all of the stimuli coming from everywhere I can be drastic and shut everything down for as long as I need to to “recenter.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s all I have for today cool cats and kittens, stay classy out there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jelani Jackson</name><email>jelani.t.jackson@gmail.com</email></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">Off in the corner contemplating my way in as it drizzles. Beautiful life ahead of me, but in this moment it doesn’t feel as such. Everyday as I work towards moving myself from where I am to where I’ll ultimately end up takes quite a bit of time, effort, and energy, some of which I feel as though I have been misusing. Part of it is me thinking of futures that wouldn’t exist, the other part is the environment. One influences the other and I’ve been contemplating making a change to the latter which could potentially render the former non-existent.</summary></entry></feed>